modeanalytics.com 2019-12-04

# Privacy Policy | Mode

This Privacy Policy describes the personal information and certain other information that we obtain through the Mode website (the “Site”) or through our data analysis product available on this Site (the “Service”), as well as how we use such information, the means by which we maintain it, and the choices you have about the information. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. 

Note that by accessing this Site or the Service, you accept the practices and terms set forth in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site or the Service. 

Mode is a participant in the U.S. Department of Commerce's EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and has certified that we adhere to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Principles. Mode is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission. 

For more information about the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework, visit the [U.S. Department of Commerce's Privacy Shield website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome). 

Mode is committed to compliance with the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) as applicable. If you or your organization is required under the GDPR to enter into a data processing agreement with Mode, please contact us at [privacy@modeanalytics.com](mailto:privacy@modeanalytics.com) to obtain a copy of our data processing addendum. 

##  What information do we collect from users of the Service or this Site, and how do we use it? 

**Registration**

Before you can use the Service, we will ask that you set up an account by providing us with your email address and name, and generating a username and password. This information will be used for identification purposes. It will also be used to communicate with you regarding your account, updates to the Service, activity within the Service, and other Mode goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you would prefer not to be notified about any of the items in the previous sentence, please email us at [privacy@modeanalytics.com](mailto:privacy@modeanalytics.com). 

The Service contains two primary functions – a "public" function and a "private" function. You have the option to use the public function, the private function, or both. 

The "public" function enables users to publicly share data with all users of the Service, as well as queries and associated data analyses, and to access, manipulate and collaborate on the data, queries and data analyses shared with the public function by other users. 

The "private" function enables users of each private group to share data, as well as queries and associated data analyses, only with other authorized users of that particular private group, and to access, manipulate and collaborate on the data, queries and data analyses shared by such other users of such private group. The private function is only available for registered users as either a free version with limited functionality or as a fee-payable premium Service. 

When you register for the premium Service, which is described more fully in our Terms of Service, we may collect all information necessary to complete the transaction, including your name, credit card information, billing information and shipping information. This information may be shared with third party vendors who process and fulfill your purchases. When you submit credit card numbers, the information is processed by our third party vendors. 

**Your Profile**

When available, you may also set up your profile on the Service and submit certain information to be displayed on your profile. This may include a photo of you, a short bio, links to your presence on other social media sites, and other information that you think other users might want to know about you. Please keep in mind that all information that you submit for display in your profile, including any personal information, will be viewable by other users of the Service. We may use this information to facilitate the Service, such as to suggest that other users follow you on the Service based on the information you provide. You can add or remove personal information from your profile on the Service in the Settings section. 

**Your Data Postings, Comments and Other Work**

As set forth in our Terms of Service, as a registered user you may upload data to the Service or post various queries, comments, analyses and other content on the data or work made available on the Service by other users. Please keep in mind that all such content that you provide to the Service (“Your Content”), including any personal or otherwise sensitive or confidential information about you or others included in Your Content, will be viewable by other registered users of the Service, as well as unregistered visitors to the Service, in accordance with the privacy settings that you specify when uploading, posting or otherwise creating Your Content on the Service. You may provide and upload Your Content and make it available to the public, using the public function. You may also provide and upload Your Content privately, using the private function. Mode will not be responsible if you incorrectly designate Your Content for Mode’s public function, and publicly disclose Your Content that you intended to remain confidential or private. The premium Service has certain functionality (“secret embeds” or “white label embeds”) that allows you to expose Your Content created in Mode’s private function to people who are not authenticated to the Service. Mode will not be responsible if you expose private information using this or similar features. We use Your Content and any personal information contained in it to facilitate the Service. 

**Usage Data and Cookies**

We collect certain statistical data, analytics, trends and usage information derived from your use of the Service. We collect some of this information through the use of cookies. A cookie is a small piece of data that a website stores on a visitor's computer, and then the visitor's browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Cookies are intended to make using the Service and this Site easier by, among other things, saving your preferences for you. We use cookies to record information about your session which may include your IP address, browser and device type, and which pages you access on the Site. You may be able to change the preferences in your browser or device to prevent or limit your device's acceptance of cookies, but this may prevent you from taking advantage of some of our features. We may use this data in aggregate form to help diagnose problems with the Site and Service, and to improve and personalize the Service. For example, we may use cookies to deliver content tailored to your interests. 

**Third-Party Integrated Services**

We may implement certain third-party offerings in the Service, enabling such third parties to collect information about you or your online activities across different websites and over time through your use of the Service. Please note that any information collected through such integrated technologies is collected directly by these third parties for use (in part) by such third parties, subject to their own privacy practices and policies. 

**Correspondence**

If you correspond with us via email, we may gather in a file specific to you the information that you submit. This includes information provided for support purposes. 

**Promotions**

We will collect information you give us when you participate in any promotion sponsored by Mode, such as a live event or contest. You will typically be asked to provide your name and email address. We store this information in our database and will use it to communicate with you about the promotion. We may also use this information to promote the Service to you in the future, unless you inform us that you opt out from receiving such communications. 

##  To whom does Mode disclose information about you that we collect through the Service? 

We may disclose personal or other information collected about you through the Service or this Site in any of the following situations: 

  * In furtherance of providing the Service, Mode may disclose certain information collected about you through the Service to other users of the Service authorized to receive such information. 
  * We may disclose information that we collect about you to our affiliates, and to third-party contractors who perform services for Mode in connection with the Site and/or the Service or to complete or confirm a transaction that you conduct with us. We contractually require these affiliates and third parties to keep personal information confidential and use it only for the purposes for which we disclose it to them. 
  * As noted, information about you collected by third-party services integrated with the Site or the Service will be disclosed to such third parties. 
  * We may disclose the results of aggregated data about you and other users without restriction. In these situations, we do not disclose to these entities any information that could be used to personally identify you. 
  * We may disclose information about you as part of a merger, acquisition or other sale or transfer of all or substantially all of Mode's assets or business. 
  * We may disclose information about you to the government or to third parties under certain circumstances when legally obligated to do so, such as in connection with suspected illegal activity in connection with the Service or this Site, or to respond to a subpoena, court order or other legal process. We reserve the right to release information collected through the Service or this Site to law enforcement, public authorities or other government officials, as we, in our sole discretion, deem necessary or appropriate, including to meet national security requirements. 
  * We may disclose any information that we believe is necessary to enforce or apply our Terms of Service and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Mode, our employees, our users, or others. 
  * We may disclose information for any other purpose with your consent. 

As described in the Privacy Shield Principles, Mode is accountable for personal data that it receives and subsequently transfers to third parties. If third parties that process personal data on our behalf do so in a manner that does not comply with the Privacy Shield Principles, we are accountable, unless we prove that we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. 

##  Is information transferred internationally? 

We are a global business based in the United States, and we may transfer data globally to be processed by us or our service providers in order to provide the Service to you or for such other purposes as set forth in this policy. If you are not a resident of the U.S., you hereby consent and agree that we may collect, process, use, and store your information, as discussed in this policy, outside your resident jurisdiction, including in the U.S. Please be aware that U.S. law and the laws of other countries where we may store and process your information may offer different levels of protection for information than may be available in your country. 

##  What security measures do we employ for information about you collected through the Service or this Site? 

Security is very important to us. We encourage you to read our security documentation at https://mode.com/security/. 

To help protect the privacy of data we collect through the Service, we employ measures intended to be consistent with industry best practices for security and encryption in data transmission and storage. However, you should keep in mind that the Site and the Service are run on software, hardware and networks, any component of which may, from time to time, require maintenance or experience problems or breaches of security beyond our control. We process payments securely using an industry-accepted Payment Gateway, and do not store any billing information on our own servers. 

Please also be aware that despite our best intentions and the guidelines outlined in this Privacy Policy, no data transmission over the Internet or encryption method can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. 

##  What is Mode’s data retention policy? 

Mode will retain your personal information only for as long as reasonably necessary for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. Please be aware that we may also be required to retain your personal information for legal and accounting reasons. In addition, for our records, we may retain original and updated information for reasons such as technical constraints, dispute resolution, fraud prevention, troubleshooting and agreement enforcement, or in other cases where we reasonably believe that we have a legitimate reason to do so. In particular, Mode will retain your personal information for as long as required to service the needs of our customers; for instance, to allow a customer to determine which of its employees created a particular report on the Mode platform, or to allow customers to reactivate their accounts with Mode. 

##  How can you correct, update, delete, or make choices regarding the information about you that is stored by Mode? 

You may correct, update or delete information that we collect about you by managing your account on the Service in the Settings section. This includes the addition or removal of certain personal information (except your name, email address, username and password, which we require of all users to maintain their accounts), as well as your preferences for the types of communications you receive from us. If you wish for your entire Mode account and all related personal information to be deleted, you may contact us at [privacy@modeanalytics.com](mailto:privacy@modeanalytics.com). 

At any time, you may object to the processing of your personal information, on legitimate grounds, except if otherwise permitted by applicable law. 

You have the right to receive your personal information in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and the right to transmit your personal information to another service provider without hindrance from Mode. 

At this time, Mode does not support “Do Not Track” preferences that may be available in your browser for letting websites know that you do not want them collecting certain kinds of information. Specifically, if you turn on the Do Not Track setting on your browser, the Service and the Site are not currently capable of following whatever Do Not Track preferences you set. Currently no common industry or legal standard for Do Not Track has been adopted by industry groups. We will make efforts to monitor developments around Do Not Track browser technology and the implementation of a standard. For more information about Do Not Track, visit donottrack.us. 

##  What are the policies of linked websites and other third parties? 

This Privacy Policy only addresses the use and disclosure of information collected from you by Mode through this Site or the Service. You should be aware that when you are using the Site or the Service, you may be directed to other websites that are beyond our control or be interfacing with third-party integrated services. We would expect most, if not all, of these third parties will collect information about you when you use their offerings. However, Mode is not responsible for the privacy practices of third parties, regardless whether they are linked or otherwise connected to this Site or the Service. We encourage you to read the posted privacy policy whenever interacting with any third-party website or other offering. 

##  What is our policy on children users of the Service? 

The Service and this Site are not directed to children under 13. If you learn that your minor child has provided us with personal information without your consent, please contact us. 

##  What law governs my use of the Service? 

By choosing to use the Site or the Service or otherwise provide information to Mode, you agree that any dispute over privacy or the terms contained in this Privacy Policy will be governed by the law of the State of California. You also agree to abide by any limitation on damages contained in our Terms of Service or other agreement that we have with you. This does not prevent consumers in the European Union from bringing a claim to enforce their consumer rights in relation to this Policy in their local courts. 

##  What additional rights do California residents have? 

California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits users of our Site or Service who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us at either the physical address or the email address noted below. 

##  What are the terms regarding any future changes to this Privacy Policy? 

Mode reserves the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy from time to time, with any such changes to be effective prospectively. Please visit this page periodically so that you will be apprised of any such changes. Your continued use of the Service or the Site after any modification to this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such modification. 

##  How can you contact us with any questions or concerns? 

We have appointed a data protection officer (“DPO”) who is responsible for overseeing our privacy practices. If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, please contact our DPO by: 

  * Mail: Mode Analytics, Attn: Data Protection Officer, 208 Utah St., Suite 400, San Francisco, CA 94103 
  * Or by e-mail at [privacy@modeanalytics.com](mailto:privacy@modeanalytics.com)

and we will work with you towards a resolution. 

If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, you can also submit your complaint to Privacy Trust, an independent third party. Visit <https://www.privacytrust.com/drs/mode> to file a complaint. 

Finally, EU residents may seek redress for their complaint using a binding arbitration mechanism, provided they have taken the following steps: (1) raised their complaint directly with us and provided us the opportunity to resolve the issue; (2) made use of the independent dispute resolution mechanism identified above; and (3) raised the issue through the relevant data protection authority and allowed the U.S. Department of Commerce an opportunity to resolve the complaint. For more information on binding arbitration, see U.S. Department of Commerce's Privacy Shield Framework: Annex I (Binding Arbitration) at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction>. 

Last Updated: April 26, 2019
